

BUSE DÖNMEZ ZERMAN

SENIOR SYSTEM ENGINEER

+90-507-355-0316 busedonmez95@gmail.com

I completed my undergraduate study at Bilkent University, Department of Electrical and Electronics Engineering. As a system engineer, I have three years of experience in avionics and air defense systems. My duties and responsibilities are performing system level software testing for command and control systems and test documentation, designing operational scenarios for air defense systems, safety analyses (FHA, FTA, FMECA, etc.), risk management, action item management, requirement management and all stages of product development and testing including system design, preparing system engineering documentation, production tracking, integration, system level testing, on-site installation.

EXPERIENCE

AYESAŞ, NOV 2019 - PRESENT

SENIOR SYSTEM ENGINEER, NOV 2022 - PRESENT

SYSTEM ENGINEER, NOV 2019 - NOV 2022

Participated in avionics and air defense systems projects. My duties and responsibilities are;

- Designing operational scenarios for air defense systems.
- Performing system level software testing for command and control systems and test documentation.
- Requirement management, system design, preparing system engineering documentation, production tracking, integration, system level testing, and on-site installation.
- FHA, FTA, FMECA, and other safety analyses.
- Risk management and action item management.

ASELSAN, JUL 2018 – AUG 2018

INTERN

Worked on rectifiers, brushless motors, switched-mode power supplies, battery charging systems (CC-CV), and research on SMBus.

NETELSAN, AUG 2017 – SEP 2017

INTERN

Involved in the installation and design of diaphones, fire alarm systems, smoke sensors, and various lighting systems that are developed in the R&D department

EDUCATION

BILKENT UNIVERSITY, 2014 – 2019

ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING, 2.36/4.00 (75/100)

• English preparatory school (1 year)

ANKARA ATATÜRK HIGH SCHOOL, 2009 – 2014 HIGH SCHOOL

• German & English preparatory school (1 year)

SKILLS

MS VisioJIRA

SVNSAP

Windchill

DOORS

LTSpice

MS Office

Java

VHDL

Matlab

CERTIFICATES AND TRAININGS

- SAE ARP4761 (Safety Assessment Process & Propulsion), TEI (08/2020) & SSA (09/2020)
- DO-254 Training, AFuzion Inc, Vance Hilderman (09/2020)
- Introduction to System Engineering Training, TEI (09/2020)
- System Safety Assessment Process Training, TEI (09/2020)
- SHT-21 (Part 21) Airworthiness Training, TEI (09/2020)
- DOORS Training, AYESAŞ (10/2020)
- Windchill FMECA Training, Informatik (04/2021)
- Windchill Advanced FTA Training, Informatik (04/2021)
- Introduction to Systems Modelling Training, Savunma Sanayii Akademi (SSA) (12/2021)
- Applied Reliability and FMECA Analyses Training, TR Eğitim ve Teknoloji (12/2021)

LANGUAGES

- Turkish Native
- English Advanced (C2) Education medium is English since 2014
- German Pre-Intermediate (B1)

MEMBERSHIP & SOCIAL ACTIVITIES

- The Chamber of Electrical Engineers (EMO), Member (2017-Present)
- IEEE, Member (2018-2019)
- The Educational Volunteers Foundation of Turkey (TEGV), Volunteer (2018-2019)